Guide to the Arthur A. Allen papers,1899-1968,
Allen, Arthur A. papers,1899-1968,
- Series IX. Papers and Reprints by Others
  - By Last Name of Author: J-P
    - "The Diving Ability of the Black Duck", 1940 (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - "The Starling in Ontario", 1934 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - "In the Land of Coca", undated (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - "Frederick W. Loetscher, Jr. - 4 Items, 1950-1956 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - "The Companion in the Environment of the Bird", 1935 (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - "Storker och Hargrar", undated (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - "The Golden Peasant Hen and the Domestic Cock Hybrids Obtained by Means of Artificial Insemination", 1953 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - "A Classification of Recent Birds", 1951 (Box 131, Folder 20)
    - "The Protection of Domesticated Animals", 1913 (Box 131, Folder 21)
    - "Bird Protection Laws Show Progress", undated (Box 131, Folder 22)
    - Captain Bellinhausen's Voyage 1819-1821", 1947 (Box 131, Folder 23)
    - "Conservation for Everybody", undated (Box 131, Folder 24)
    - "Posterity's World", 1938 (Box 131, Folder 25)
    - "How Biology Came to Knox College", 1945 (Box 131, Folder 26)
    - Margaret M. Nice - 3 items, 1929, 1933 (Box 131, Folder 27)
    - "The Rodents of New Caledonia", 1953 (Box 131, Folder 28)
    - "Notes on the Nomenclature of Certain Genera of Birds", 1905 (Box 131, Folder 29)
    - "'Audubons at Echo Lake, 1928", 1928 (Box 131, Folder 30)
    - "A Revision of the Philippine Elegant Titmouse", 1958 (Box 131, Folder 31)
    - "Systematic Notes on North American Birds: The Waterfowl (Anatidae)", 1957 (Box 131, Folder 32)
    - "Taxonomy and Nomenclature of Three Species of Lonchura (Aues: Estrilidinae)", 1958 (Box 131, Folder 33)
    - "Premiere Capture du Becasseau de Baird en France", 1958 (Box 131, Folder 34)
    - T. Gilbert Pearson - 2 Items, 1924, 1933 (Box 131, Folder 35)
    - "Fifty Years of Bird Protection in the United States", 1933 (Box 131, Folder 36)
    - "A Bird with a Powder Puff", undated (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - By Last Name of Author: S-U, W
    - "The Bird Course at the Allegheny School of Natural History", undated (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - "Sensible Reforesting", 1920 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - "Non-adaptive Behavior Resulting from a Series of Defeats in Fighting Mice", 1953 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - "Some Problems of Heredity and Social Behavior", 1953 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - "Man and Bird Together: A Portrait of Albert R. Brand and Bird-song Recording", 1942 (Box 132, Folder 6, 7)
    - "Coyotes Protected", 1953 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - "Eggs of Reptiles and Birds Compared with Some Unusual Examples of the Latter", 1916 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - "First Descriptions of North American Birds", 1936 (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - "Bird Casualties at a Leon County, Florida TV Tower", 1962 (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - "Historical Data on a Specimen of Sooty Tern", 1941 (Box 132, Folder 12)
    - "Homing Instinct in the Bank Swallow", 1941 (Box 132, Folder 13)
    - "The Taxidermists' Manual", 1873 (Box 132, Folder 14)
    - "The Ivory-billed Woodpecker", 1942 (Box 132, Folder 15)
    - "Tierstimmen" (Animal Voices", 1951 (Box 132, Folder 16)
    - National Geographic Society articles, undated (Box 132, Folder 17)
    - "Tarsal Feathering of Ruffled Grouse", 1941 (Box 132, Folder 18)
    - "A New Race of Cuckoo…", 1951 (Box 132, Folder 19)
    - Occurrence of the Wandering and Black-browed Albatross on New Caledonia", 1947 (Box 132, Folder 20)
    - "The Present Status of the Kagu", 1948 (Box 132, Folder 21)
    - The White-throated pigeon nesting on the ground in New Caledonia, 1949 (Box 132, Folder 22)
    - "Birds and Mammals of the Mesa de San Diego, Puebla, Mexico", 1957 (Box 132, Folder 23)
    - "Systematics and Biology of the Singing Quail", 1957 (Box 132, Folder 24)
    - "Notes on Birds of the Veracruz Coastal Plain", 1951 (Box 132, Folder 25)
    - "Feather Arrangement, Development, and Molt of the Long-billed Marsh Wren", 1936 (Box 132, Folder 26)
    - "Revised Classification for the Birds of the World", 1951 (Box 132, Folder 27)
    - "Systematic Classification for the Birds of the World", 1940 (Box 132, Folder 28)
    - "Systematic Classification for the Birds of the World, Revised and Ammended", 1934 (Box 132, Folder 29)
    - "What we Owe to Agassiz", 1907 (Box 132, Folder 30)
    - "Flashlight Apparatus", undated (Box 132, Folder 31)
- Series X. Photographic and Motion Picture Materials
  - Photographs and Some Sketches
    - Backdoor of Buena Ventura, 1912 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - "Columbia Volume II: Cali-Amaguer", 1912 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - "Columbia Volume III: Valle de Pappas-Giradot", 1912 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - "Columbia Volume IV: Salencio-Ancon", 1912 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - "Grallaria Allen", 1912 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - "Birds of the Cat-tails and Sedges" (sic), 1905-1909 (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - "Birds about Buildings", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - "Birds of the Forest Floor", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - "Birds of the Gorges", 1906-1908 (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - "Birds of the Open Field", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - "Birds of the Orchard", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 11)
    - "Birds of the Tree Tops", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 12)
    - "Birds of the Undergrowth, Low Bushes", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 13)
    - "Birds of the Undergrowth, Low Trees, and Tall Bushes", 1903-1908 (Box 133, Folder 14)
    - "Birds that Nest in Holes", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 15)
    - "The Hawks and Owls", 1904-1908 (Box 133, Folder 16)
    - "The Tree Swallows, Renwick Marsh, Ithaca NY, 1908 (Box 133, Folder 17)
    - "Wild Animals I Have Known", 1906-1908 (Box 133, Folder 18)
    - "The Ivory-billed Woodpecker", 1924-1934 (Box 133, Folder 19)
    - "The Curlew's Secret", 1948 (Box 133, Folder 20)
    - "The Peregrine Falcon", undated (Box 133, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1907-1915 (Box 133, Folder 22)
    - Early color prints by Arthur Allen, undated (Box 133, Folder 23)
    - Early sound equipment, undated (Box 133, Folder 24)
    - "Trip to Panama", 1944, 1945 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - "Robin Feeding Young", 1947 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - "Birds in Action", 1953 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - "Birds-High Speed", undated (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - "Birds in Flight", undated (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous bird photographs, undated (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous bird photographs, undated (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - "Bob White's Reception: A Photographic Satire", undated (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Waterfowl, undated (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - "Birds in Winter", undated (Box 134, Folder 10)
    - Screech Owl, undated (Box 134, Folder 11)
    - Photos for publication, undated (Box 134, Folder 12)
    - Photos sold to National Geographic, 1962 (Box 134, Folder 13)
    - Photos for publication, undated (Box 134, Folder 14)
    - Photos for publication, undated (Box 134, Folder 15)
    - Birds, nests, bird houses and eggs", undated (Box 134, Folder 16)
    - Birds, nests and eggs, undated (Box 134, Folder 17-21)
    - Birds, 1961 (Box 134, Folder 22-23)
    - Birds and nests, 1961 (Box 134, Folder 24)
    - Birds and nests, undated (Box 134, Folder 25)
    - Birds, 1914 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Birds and waterfowl, 1998-1905 (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Birds and nests, undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Birds and waterfowl, undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - "A Baby Willet Learns to Walk", undated (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - "Birds and Their Surroundings", undated (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Photos by Arthur Allen, undated (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - Birds of prey, undated (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Waterfowl in flight, undated (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - Birds, undated (Box 135, Folder 10-11)
    - Cormorants, 1899 and undated (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Cranes and Rails, undated (Box 135, Folder 13)
    - Divers, undated (Box 135, Folder 14)
    - Ducks, undated (Box 135, Folder 15)
    - Flamingos, undated (Box 135, Folder 16)
    - Geese and Swans, undated (Box 135, Folder 17)
    - Grebe, undated (Box 135, Folder 18)
    - Gulls, undated (Box 135, Folder 19)
    - Hawks, undated (Box 135, Folder 20)
    - Herons, undated (Box 135, Folder 21)
    - Owls and Stilts, undated (Box 135, Folder 22)
    - Pelicans, undated (Box 135, Folder 23)
    - Puffins and Plovers, undated (Box 135, Folder 24)
    - Sandpipers, undated (Box 135, Folder 25)
    - Terns, undated (Box 135, Folder 26)
    - Prints for publicity, undated (Box 135, Folder 27)
    - Birds, undated (Box 135, Folder 28)
    - Louis Agassiz Fuertes, 1917 and undated (Box 135, Folder 29)
    - Stalking Birds, undated (Box 135, Folder 30-33)
    - "Ambassadors of Good Will", undated (Box 135, Folder 34)
    - "Bird Book", undated (Box 135, Folder 35-36)
    - National Geographic color prints, undated (Box 135, Folder 37)
    - "Useful Birds of America", undated (Box 135, Folder 38)
    - "Birdnests of France", undated (Box 135, Folder 39)
    - Frogs, undated (Box 135, Folder 40)
    - Chipmunk, undated (Box 135, Folder 41)
    - Mink, undated (Box 135, Folder 42)
    - Waterfowl, 1897-1923 (Box 135, Folder 43)
    - "Observations in Texas", 1901 (Box 135, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, 1898 (Box 135, Folder 45)
    - University Faculty, 1916 (Box 135, Folder 46)
    - Summer school classes, 1919-1931 (Box 135, Folder 47)
    - Summer school classes, 1933-1947 (Box 135, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous negatives, undated (Box 135, Folder 49)
    - Waterfowl, undated (Box 135, Folder 50)
    - Birds feeding young, 1951 (Box 135, Folder 51)
    - Photos by others, undated (Box 135, Folder 52-54)
    - To Art from Harp, 1909-1910 (Box 135, Folder 55)
    - "Starting out from Northwood", 1906 (Box 135, Folder 56)
    - "Houses for Birds", undated (Box 135, Folder 57)
    - Birds, 1923 (Box 135, Folder 58)
    - Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology Expedition to Florida and the Gulf Coast, 1958 (Box 135, Folder 59)
    - Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology Pacific Coast Expedition, 1959 (Box 135, Folder 60)
    - Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology Gulf Coast and California Expedition, 1961 (Box 135, Folder 61)
    - Photos by others, 1908-1921 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Bird houses, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - "Eagle from Amazon River", 1899 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Photos by others, undated (Box 136, Folder 4-8)
    - Drawings, sketches and photos by others, 1929-1960 (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - Bird slide business, 1944-1958 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - "Birds of the Marshes", undated (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - "Hunting the Hunters", 1924 (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - "Bird Homes" and "Bird Life", 1929-1930 (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - "Bird Migration", 1931 (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - "Birds of the Finger Lakes Region", 1925, 1930 (Box 136, Folder 15)
    - Film manuscripts by others, 1930, 1931 (Box 136, Folder 16)
    - "Pacific Coast Salmon", 1927, 1930 (Box 136, Folder 17)
    - "Hunting with a Microphone and a Color Camera", undated (Box 136, Folder 18)
    - "Footbridge for a Dam", 1923 (Box 136, Folder 19)
    - "Pigeon House", undated (Box 136, Folder 20)
    - "Birds of the Garden" and "Birds of Indiana", 1921 (Box 136, Folder 21)
    - "North with the Birds", undated (Box 136, Folder 22)
    - Photos for tests, undated (Box 136, Folder 23)
    - Stilt and Semipalmated Sandpiper, undated (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Study in black and white, undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Pine Siskin, undated (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - Male Scarlet Tanager and Young, undated (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - A Raccoon adrift in the cove, undated (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Young Screech Owls, undated (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Marsh Hawk nests in the Sanctuary Marsh, undated (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Common Summerbird of the Sanctuary, undated (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - White-crowned Sparrow, undated (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Rustic bridge and bird feeding station, 1917 (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - A winter Tree Sparrow, undated (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Winter Crows in the Sanctuary, undated (Box 137, Folder 12)
    - Dredging Fall Creek, 1914 (Box 137, Folder 13)
    - Canada Geese, undated (Box 137, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Rail approaching nest in the Sanctuary Marsh, undated (Box 137, Folder 15)
    - The Comstock Bird Fountain, undated (Box 137, Folder 16)
    - Chipmunk, undated (Box 137, Folder 17)
    - Yellow-legs on the shores of Cayuga Lake, undated (Box 137, Folder 18)
    - Meadowlark, undated (Box 137, Folder 19)
    - Early spring in the Sanctuary, undated (Box 137, Folder 20)
    - First field day in the Sanctuary, 1915 (Box 137, Folder 21)
    - Herons on the lake shore in August, undated (Box 137, Folder 22)
    - Entrance to the Bird Sanctuary, 1917 (Box 137, Folder 23)
    - How birds respond to kindness, undated (Box 137, Folder 24)
    - Red-throated Loon, 1929 (Box 137, Folder 25)
    - Herring Gull, 1929 (Box 137, Folder 26)
    - Female Cardinal and young, 1931 (Box 137, Folder 27)
    - Atlantic Puffins, 1929 (Box 137, Folder 28)
    - Grouse and breeding pens, 1932 (Box 137, Folder 29)
    - Black Guillemots, 1929 (Box 137, Folder 30)
    - Mother feeding young, undated (Box 137, Folder 31)
    - Woodpecker, undated (Box 137, Folder 32)
    - Birds in relation to agriculture, undated (Box 137, Folder 33)
    - Screech Owl, undated (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Screech Owl, by day and by night, undated (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Screech Owl feeding salamander to young, undated (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Ruby-throated Humming Bird, undated (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Photographing a Bittern, undated (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Bob-white, undated (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Killer scolding, undated (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Western Willet - Cayuga Lake, undated (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Kingfisher with small sucker, undated (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - Northern Shrike or butcher bird, undated (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - Goldfinch, undated (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Tree Sparrow, undated (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Bank Swallow, undated (Box 138, Folder 14)
    - Captive Great Horned Owl with rat, undated (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Ring-necked Pheasant, undated (Box 138, Folder 16)
    - Scaup Ducks on Cayuga Lake in winter, undated (Box 138, Folder 17)
    - Louisiana water Thrush, undated (Box 138, Folder 18)
    - White-throated Sparrow and Song Sparrow, undated (Box 138, Folder 19)
    - Evening Grosbeak driving House Sparrow from feeding log, undated (Box 138, Folder 20)
    - Bird with nest, undated (Box 138, Folder 21)
    - Canada Goose with eggs, undated (Box 138, Folder 22)
    - Bird in tree limb, undated (Box 138, Folder 23)
    - American Eider, 1929 (Box 138, Folder 24)
    - Grouse with feeding bins, undated (Box 138, Folder 25)
    - Hummingbird on spoon, undated (Box 138, Folder 26)
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker, undated (Box 138, Folder 27)
    - American Ornithologists Union, 1913 (Box 138, Folder 28)
    - Portrait of Arthur Allen, undated (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Dolly and a Hummingbird, undated (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Peregrine Falcon, undated (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Duck Hawk charging the photographer, undated (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Ospreys and their nest, undated (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Male Marsh Hawk at its nest, undated (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Louis Agassiz Fuertes and his favorite bird - and immature Duck Hawk, undated (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Hawk and young, undated (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Early sound equipment, undated (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - "Stalking birds…", undated (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Hawk, undated (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Goshawk attacking a female Mallard, undated (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - "Ground covers…", undated (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Ducks, undated (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - Birds, undated (Box 139, Folder 15)
    - Cedar Waxwing, Wood duck, undated (Box 139, Folder 16)
    - Stalking with a Color Camera", undated (Box 139, Folder 17)
    - Prints by Richard E. Bishop, undated (Box 139, Folder 18)
    - Cardinal, undated (Box 139, Folder 19)
    - Louis Agassiz Fuertes Memorial site, 1927 (Box 139, Folder 20)
    - Maps, undated (Box 139, Folder 21)
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker, undated (Box 139, Folder 22)
    - Various photos of Arthur Allen, undated (Box 139, Folder 23)
      Formerly in the Ornithology APC file
    - Birds and Birds nests, c. 1896-1897, undated (Box 181, Folder 3)
      Not all by Arthur Allen. Some of the photos in this box have been treated for mold damage
    - Birds, undated (Box 181, Folder 4-6)
    - Birds, mammal, and nature scenes, undated (Box 181, Folder 7-12)
      Includes a photograph of a Fuertes backdrop for an exhibit at Museum of Natural History
    - Copper plate printing blocks of Arthur Allen photographs (Box 182)
    - Bird Structure and Development Charts, undated (Mapcase-folder 3)
      Oversize
    - Photographs - various, 1932 (Mapcase-folder 4)
    - Mounted Bird Photographs, 1920-1948 (Mapcase-folder 5)
    - Glenside Bird Sighting Charts and blueprint, 1918-1938 (Mapcase-folder 6)
  - Motion Picture Film Clips
    - Jungle Acoustics Project, 1941-1957 (Box 140)
      Some clips on deposit at the Laboratory of Ornithology
    - Various clips of birds, toads, and filming equipment, undated (Box 141)
    - Jungle Acoustics Project: Panama, 1944 (Box 142)
    - Expeditions: Panama, Churchill, and labeled by bird species, 1944-1945 (Box 143)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1937-1942 (Box 144)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1938-1943 (Box 145)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1938-1944 (Box 146)
    - Various clips birds, animals, insects and plants, 1939-1943 (Box 147)
    - Various clips birds and mammals, 1939-1947 (Box 148)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1947-1951 (Box 149)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1951-1952 (Box 150)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1953-1955 (Box 151)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1956-1962 (Box 152)
    - Various clips by bird species, 1946-1961 (Box 153)
    - Various clips: birds, mammals and personal, 1941-1962 (Box 154)
  - Videos
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker (from films 153 and 154), V-64
      Type C Master - NOT FOR USE, use DVD-688
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker (from films 153 and 154), V-65
      Copy of V-64 - NOT FOR USE, use DVD-688
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker (from films 153 and 154), V-136
      VHS copy - NOT FOR USE, use DVD-688
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker (from films 153 and 154), V-439
      Beta SP dub of Type C Master - NOT FOR USE, use DVD-688
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker (from films 153 and 154), DVD-688
      USE COPY
  - Glass Plate Negatives
    - Miscellaneous scenery and nature photographs, 1898-1925 (Box 155)
    - Miscellaneous Birds, undated (Box 156)
    - Miscellaneous Birds, undated (Box 161)
    - Ducks, Flickers and Miscellaneous Birds, 1900-1915 (Box 166)
    - Various birds and mammals, c. 1908-1939 (Box 176)
    - 114 negatives of various birds, c. 1909-1928 (Box 177)
    - 84 negatives of various birds, c. 1906-1929 (Box 178)
    - 89 negatives of various birds, c. 1909-1914 (Box 179)
    - 115 negatives of various birds, c. 1905-1918 (Box 184)
  - Glass Slides
    - Ivory-billed Woodpecker, 1924 (Box 162)
    - Fuertes - Drawer 1, undated (Box 165, Folder 1-3)
    - Fuertes - Drawer 2, Miscellaneous birds and animals, undated (Box 165, Folder 4)
    - Fuertes - Drawer 3, Yucatan, undated (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Archival - Drawer 4, undated (Box 165, Folder 6-7)
    - Archival - Drawer 5, undated (Box 165, Folder 8-9)
    - Bird File: Adjutant - Bobolink, undated (Box 165, Folder 10)
    - Bird File: Bobwhite - Cowbird, undated (Box 165, Folder 11)
    - Bird File: Crane - Crow, undated (Box 165, Folder 12)
    - Bird File: Cuckoo - Duck, Mallard, undated (Box 165, Folder 13)
    - Bird File: Duck, Merganser - Emeu, undated (Box 165, Folder 14)
    - Bird File: Flicker - Grebe, undated (Box 165, Folder 15)
    - Bird File: Grosbeak, Evening - Guillemot, undated (Box 165, Folder 16)
    - Bird File: Hawk - House (bird), undated (Box 165, Folder 17)
    - Bird File: Hummingbird - Longspur, undated (Box 165, Folder 18)
    - Bird File: Loon-Ovenbird, undated (Box 165, Folder 19)
    - Bird File: Owl - Oyster Catcher, undated (Box 165, Folder 20)
    - Bird File: Pelican - Quail, undated (Box 165, Folder 21)
    - Bird File: Rail - Red-wing, undated (Box 165, Folder 22)
    - Bird File: Rhea - Sandpiper, undated (Box 165, Folder 23)
    - Bird File: Sapsucker - Snipe, undated (Box 165, Folder 24)
    - Bird File: Sparrow - Swallow, White-bellied, undated (Box 165, Folder 25)
    - Bird File: Swan - Thrush, undated (Box 165, Folder 26)
    - Bird File: Tinamon - Warbler, Nashville, undated (Box 165, Folder 27)
    - Bird File: Warbler, Pronothotary - Woodcock, undated (Box 165, Folder 28)
    - Bird File: Woodpecker - Wren, undated (Box 165, Folder 29)
    - Coloration, undated (Box 165, Folder 30)
    - Game Birds, undated (Box 165, Folder 31-32)
    - History of Bird Art, undated (Box 165, Folder 33)
    - "Hunting with a Camera", undated (Box 165, Folder 34-35)
    - Mammal File: Antelope - Mouse, undated (Box 165, Folder 36)
    - Mammal File: Muskrat - Woodchuck, undated (Box 165, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Animals and Birds, undated (Box 165, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 165, Folder 39)
    - Environment, undated (Box 165, Folder 40)
    - Education Record Slides, undated (Box 165, Folder 41-44)
    - Single slides with captions, undated (Box 165, Folder 45)
- Series XI. Phonographic Records and Sound Recordings
  - Phonographic Record Booklets
    - "Song and Garden Birds of North America", 1963 (Box 157, Folder 1-2)
      Contains information about recordings
    - "The Sparrows", 1963 (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - " Song-birds of America in Song and Story", 1954 (Box 157, Folder 5-6)
    - "Upland game Birds and Waterfowl of America and their Calls", 1960 (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - "Dawn in the Duck Blind", 1963 (Box 157, Folder 8-10)
    - "Bird Songs in Your Garden", 1960 (Box 157, Folder 11-12)
    - "The Warbler Family", undated (Box 157, Folder 13)
    - "Marsh-Land Mysteries of Sight and Sound", 1963 (Box 157, Folder 14)
    - "American Bird Songs", undated (Box 157, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 157, Folder 16-17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 157, Folder 18)
  - Phonograph Records
    - "The Songs of Wild Birds", 1933; SR-5557-SR-5561, 5564 (Box 160)
    - Canada Warbler, undated; SR-5562 (Box 160)
      Note reads: 1st variation - excellent
    - untitled recording, undated; SR-5563 (Box 160)
    - Metal record "stampers" of an unknown sound recording, SR-5549 and SR-5555 (Box 174)
      Possibly from the Jungle Acoustics Project
  - Tape Recordings
    - Laboratory of Ornithology Council meeting, May 1962; 1/4" reel TR-9927 (Box 158)
    - Arthur Allen voice and script for "Listen to the Marshes", c. 1955-1963; 1/4" reel TR-9928 (Box 158)
    - "Mr. Peepers" my pet Parakeet - Parakeet Talk, 1955; 1/4" reel TR-9929 (Box 158)
    - "An Evening in Sapsucker Woods", c. 1955-1963; 1/4" reel TR-9930 (Box 158)
    - "The Story of Sapsucker Woods" by Arthur Allen (Copy), 1960; 1/4" reel TR-9931 (Box 158)
    - Toucans - in the Aviary, 1958; 1/4" reel TR-9932 (Box 158)
    - Laboratory of Ornithology Council meeting, 1963; 1/4" reel TR-9933 (Box 158)
    - Laboratory of Ornithology Council meeting, December 1962; 1/4" reel TR-9934 (Box 158)
    - "The Story of Sapsucker Woods" by Arthur Allen (Original), 1960; 1/4" reel TR-9935 (Box 158)
    - "American Bird Songs" Volume 1 - Records 1-5, undated; 1/4" reel TR-9936 (Box 158)
    - "American Bird Songs" Volume 2 - Records 1-4, undated; 1/4" reel TR-9937 (Box 158)
    - Western Birds - Sides 1 and 2, undated; 1/4" reel TR-9938 (Box 158)